Finding Aid for Department of Journalism (University of Michigan) research papers, 1967-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Journalism (University of Michigan) research papers 1967-1978
University of Michigan. Dept. of Journalism.
87127 Bimu C26 2
Research papers, 1967-1979, of students in journalism at the University of Michigan; contain essays relating to the history of Michigan newspapers and journalists, and the development of radio and television broadcasting; include papers concerning newspapers in Adrian, Ann Arbor, Detroit, and Grand Rapids, and the journalistic efforts of Father Charles Coughlin, Henry Ford, and Gerald L. K. Smith.
2 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by Professor John D. Stevens (donor no. 4666 ), beginning in 1969.
The record group is open without restriction.
The study of journalism at the University of Michigan began in 1890/91 when Fred Newton Scott, assistant professor of rhetoric, started a course on rapid writing. This course was dropped in 1893/94, and no further journalistic instruction was offered until 1903 when Scott brought together various courses to form a Rhetoric Department. One of these courses was Rhetoric 13 (Newspaper writing), which continued with modest additions until 1916 when a special program in journalism was-established. In 1921/22, the name of the Department of Rhetoric was officially changed to the Department of Rhetoric and Journalism to reflect more accurately the increased emphasis on this discipline. In 1929, journalism became a separate department with the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts (LSA).
Over the years the curriculum of the department has expanded. In 1933 the department began to offer graduate courses. In 1938, this part of the program was revised so that only those with a BA in journalism would be admitted. One of the strong points of the curriculum has been the experience of those who taught; virtually all of the faculty have had professional experience.
Beginning in 1947, the department initiated a program entitled, "University Lectures in Journalism," which brought many major speakers to the campus. Included were famed journalists such as I.F. Stone, Edward Lamb and Russell Barnes, as well as individuals with experience in fields related to journalism, for example, civil libertarian attorneys, cartoonists, and historians. Supplementing the lecture series, the department hosted many different conferences and workshops that focused on some of the broader issues in the filed such as questions of privacy or newspaper libel.
To provide students with experience, the department in 1947 organized a system of internships. Some of these were post-BA internships allowing the student to work on actual newspapers located both in Michigan and throughout the nation. Students were also aided in their studies by a liberal scholarship program.
Beginning in 1925, the department published a laboratory newspaper, the Michigan Journalist. Published several times a year, the newspaper served as a showcase for student writing and reporting.
On July 1, 1979, the Department of Journalism merged with the Department of Speech Communication and Theatre to form the Department of Communication.
The Department of Journalism research papers collection measures 2 linear feet and consists solely of student research papers written between 1967 and 1979. The papers contain essays written regarding the history of various newspapers -- many in Michigan cities such as Adrian, Ann Arbor, Detroit and Grand Rapids; journalists and the journalistic efforts of individuals such as Father Charles Coughlin, Henry Ford, and Gerald L.K. Smith; and the development of radio and television broadcasting.
The surviving administrative records of the Department of Journalism were retained by its successor unit, the Department of Communication, and can be found in that department's records.
Subjects:
American newspapers--Michigan--Adrian.; Adrian telegram.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor courier.; Ann Arbor Sun.; Antisemitism.; Applegate, Harriet Marie.; Auburn (Mich.); Banks and banking--Michigan.; Baseball.; Bay City times.; Bay County (Mich.); Booth, George G. (George Gough), b. 1864.; Bunyan, Paul (Legendary character); CIO news.; Cheboygan (Mich.); Cheboygan tribune.; Mexican Americans--Michigan.; Civil rights news.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Clare (Mich.); Corselius, George, 1806-1849.; Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.; Crime.; The cross and the flag.; The Dearborn independent.; Depressions--1929--Michigan.; American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit Free Press.; Detroit gazette.; Detroit news.; Detroit post and tribune.; Detroit times.; The fifth estate.; Flint (Mich.); Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Forest fires--Michigan.; Foster, Theodore, 1812-1865.; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881.; Genesee County (Mich.); Gogebic County (Mich.); Gogebic explorer.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Grand Rapids press.; Hastings banner.; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951.; Hogan, Henry M.; Huron County (Mich.); Huron daily tribune.; Inkster (Mich.); Journalists--Michigan.; Labor--Michigan.; Lapeer County (Mich.); Lathers, Swift, 1889-1970.; Livingston County (Mich.); Louis, Joe, 1914-1981.; Macomb County (Mich.); Marshall (Mich.); Mears news.; Michigan chronicle.; The Michigan Daily.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); University of Michigan--Students--Periodicals.; Michigan whig.; Midland (Mich.); Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.; Mount Clemens (Mich.); Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Nader, Ralph.; African Americans--Michigan.; Newspaper carriers--Michigan.; Nosotros.; Oakland County (Mich.); Ontonagon County (Mich.); Ontonagon herald.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan.; Radulovich, Milo, 1927?-; Royal Oak daily tribune.; Saginaw County (Mich.); Saginaw news.; Saint Clair County (Mich.); Sanilac County (Mich.); Shiawassee County (Mich.); Signal of liberty.; Antislavery movements--United States.; Smith, Gerald L. K. (Gerald Lyman Kenneth), 1898-1976; Social justice.; Spanish-American War, 1898.; Storey, Wilbur F., 1819-1884.; Strikes and lockouts--Michigan.; Television broadcasting--Michigan.; Temperance--Michigan.; Tuscola County (Mich.); Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; WCHB (Radio station: Inkster, Mich.); WPAG (Radio station: Ann Arbor, Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Western statesman.; World War, 1939-1945.; Women in journalism--Michigan.; Crockett, George W.; American newspapers--Michigan--Dearborn.; Die Washtenaw post.; American newspapers--Michigan--Livingston County.; University of Michigan.; American newspapers--Michigan--Niles.; The Plaindealer.; The Spinal column.; Western emigrant.; The Michigan union.; Railroads--Michigan.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union.; Adrian daily times and expositor.; Advertising.; AFL-CIO news.; Associated Press.; Ann Arbor register.; Battle Creek enquirer and news.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; The Christian journal.; Coffman, Al.; Cook, Marshall L., 1858-1955.; Cook, William Randolph, 1866-1946.; Detroit labor news.; Detzer, Karl, 1891-1987; Dutch Americans--Michigan.; Evart review.; Flint journal.; Gladwin County record.; Hillsdale gazette.; Hillsdale whig standard.; Howard City record.; The Keweenaw miner.; Lapeer County press.; Mackinac Bridge (Mich.); McKinley, William, 1843-1901.; Michigan argus.; Michigan suffragist.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Osceola County democrat.; Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.; Peninsular courier and family visitant.; Photojournalism.; Reed City weekly clarion.; Progressivism (United States politics); Richard, Gabriel, 1767-1832.; Evening news (Sault Sainte Marie, Mich.); Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; Sports journalism.; Ufer, Robert Pormann, 1920-1981.; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America.; Washtenaw whig.; Academic freedom.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.; United States. President (1861-1865: Lincoln). Emancipation Proclamation.; Riots--Michigan--Detroit--History--20th century.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
- Student Papers undated
  - Antoniotti, Steve.
    - "Bay County, Michigan" (Box 1)
      [1]
    - "Black Newspapers and the Michigan Chronicle" (Box 1)
      [2]
    - "A Comparative Study of the Battle of Running Bulls-1937" (Box 1)
      [3]
  - Eichbauer, Paul.
    - "Economic Factors and Newspapers in Michigan" (Box 1)
      [4]
  - Eley, Rob.
    - "Nader in the News: From Publication of 'Unsafe at Any Speed', to the Automobile Manufacturers' Acceptance of Federally Regulated Safety Standards" (Box 1)
      [5]
  - Furr, Debra E.
    - " The Hastings Banner and World War I" (Box 1)
      [6]
  - Ghio, Craig.
    - "Yellow Journalism: An Influence on Small-Town Newspapers?" (Box 1)
      [7]
  - Klinger, David.
    - "Contemporary Journalism" (Box 1)
      (1967 Detroit riots)
      [8]
  - Labardee, Lorin.
    - "The Floyd Josiah Miller Story" (Box 1)
      [9]
  - Mahanic, Roger.
    - "Sensationalist Humor" " (Box 1)
      [10]
  - McCoy, Colin.
    - "CIO News and the Communists" (Box 1)
      [11]
  - Meijer, Deborah L.
    - "On Suburban Newspapers: An Interview with Henry M. Morgan, Jr" (Box 1)
      [12]
  - Meka, Julie.
    - "The Growth of Objectivity in the Reporting of the Arts: Grand Rapids Presses,1836-1900" (Box 1)
      [13]
  - Patterson,Doris
    - "The Black Press" (Box 1)
      [14]
    - "Blacks in Radio and Television" (Box 1)
      (1 tape in G-152-S)
      [15]
  - Petoskey, Barbara.
    - [A collection of Detroit Newspaper Stories] (Box 1)
      [16]
  - Rowe, K. A.
    - "The Wireless Newspapers and the Public Opinion (1906 until 1924)" (Box 1)
      [17]
  - Stone, Steven J.
    - "Student Newspapers at The University of Michigan" (Box 1)
      [18]
  - Travis, Paul.
    - "A Non-Comparative Comparison of the Detroit Media's Coverage of the Birth of Television" (Box 1)
      [19]
  - Wilson, Kenneth.
    - "Negro Radio-WCHB" (Box 1)
      (tape in G152-S)
      [20]
- Student Papers 1967
  - Engle, Cheryl, et al.
    - "News Media in Lapeer, Sanilac, Huron and Tuscola Counties" (Box 1)
      [21]
  - Hatchett, Shirley.
    - "Genesee County" (Box 1)
      [22]
  - Keebaugh, Cynthia.
    - "Shiawassee County Newspapers" (Box 1)
      [23]
  - Matsuhiro, Elizabeth.
    - "St. Clair County and Mt. Clemens" (Box 1)
      [24]
  - Pratt, Toni.
    - "Newspapers of Cities in Oakland County" (Box 1)
      [25]
  - Shutt, David M.
    - "Newspapers of Saginaw County, Michigan" (Box 1)
      [26]
  - Smith, Leonard Paul.
    - "Newspapers in Washtenaw County" (Box 1)
      [27]
  - Tegge, Constance M.
    - "History of the Newspapers of Livingstone County, Michigan" (Box 1)
      [28]
  - Wilson, Kenneth Howard.
    - "Macomb County" (Box 1)
      [29]
- Student Papers, Spring 1968
  - Wolfe, Nancy.
    - "Henry Ford's Paper Pogrom: The Dearborn Independent" (Box 1)
      [30]
- Student Papers, Winter 1969
  - Brammer, Mary Evelyn.
    - "The Media's Divided Warfare with the Controversial Henry Ford" (Box 1)
      [31]
  - Sweeny, Sherla.
    - "Father Charles Coughlin, Detroit's Famed 'Radio Priest" (Box 1)
      [32]
  - Walsh, Catherine.
    - "Vandenberg and the Press: Isolationism and Internationalism" (Box 1)
      [33]
- Student Papers, Fall 1970
  - Burstadt, Claire.
    - " The Detroit Gazette" (Box 1)
      [34]
  - Eldridge, Evelyn.
    - "A Comparison of Coverages of the Emancipation Proclamation: The Detroit Free Press and the Richmond Enquirer" (Box 1)
      [35]
  - Goltz, Daniel.
    - "The Emancipation Proclamation: A Study of Its Coverage in Two Newspapers" (Box 1)
      [36]
  - Herman, Florence.
    - " The Michigan Whig: Ann Arbor in 1835" (Box 1)
      [37]
  - Hoffman, Ellen S.
    - " The Ann Arbor Courier: 1880" (Box 1)
      [38]
  - Mahoney, Patrick R.
    - "Maximum Exposure" (Box 1)
      (concerning Frank Murphy and the Detroit press, 1923-1933)
      [39]
    - "Two Approaches to the Surrender at Appomattox Courthouse" (Box 1)
      [40]
  - Stegath, Sarah.
    - "Marshall Western Statesman, 1839". (Box 1)
      [41]
  - York, Terrall.
    - "Enemy Aliens in World War I: How Two Newspapers Reported the Public Reaction" (Box 1)
      [42]
- Student Papers, Fall 1971
  - Bloom, Andrea.
    - "Henry Ford and The Dearborn Independent" (Box 1)
      [43]
  - Cieply, Mike.
    - "The Detroit Free Press and the Advent of World War" (Box 1)
      [44]
  - Damashek, Sandra.
    - "Theodore Foster: The Man and His Work" (Box 1)
      (Signal of Liberty)
      [45]
  - Kavanagh, Eileen.
    - "Abolition in Michigan Politics: The Evidence of Ann Arbor Newspapers, 1841-1849" (Box 1)
      [46]
  - Leaphart, Elaine.
    - "Historical Overview of the Detroit Tribune" (Box 1)
      [47]
  - Storey, Jim.
    - "The Michigan Experience. Wilbur F. Storey, Editor" (Box 1)
      [48]
  - Weyand, Robert J.
    - "A Town Grows Up: A History of the Northern Michigan Settlement of Cheboygan, from the Pages of the Cheboygan Tribune" (Box 1)
      [49]
  - Wyatt, George H.
    - "'I Know No History But Today' The Dearborn Independent 1919-1923" (Box 1)
      [50]
- Student Papers, Winter 1972
  - Bush, William.
    - "Coughlin, The Banking Crisis of Detroit, and the Common Man" (Box 1)
      [51]
  - Capos, Claudia R.
    - "Adrian's Woman Editor of the 1890s" (Box 1)
      [52]
  - Golding, Andy.
    - "The History Behind the Formation of the Ann Arbor Sun" (Box 1)
      [53]
  - Horowitz, Amy.
    - "The Ann Arbor Sun: Its History and Development" (Box 1)
      [54]
  - Meijer, Hendrik.
    - "An Early History of WZZM-TV, Channel 13" (Box 1)
      [54a5]
  - Swartley, Ron.
    - " The Gogebic Explorer (June 4,1885-September 10,1885)" (Box 1)
      [55]
- Student Papers, Fall 1972
  - Lawson, L. David.
    - "Grand Rapids Newspapers and the Spanish-American War" (Box 1)
      [56]
  - Scott, Jill E.
    - "Anatomy of a Strike: The Adrian Daily Telegram" (Box 1)
      [57]
- Student Papers, Winter 1973
  - Anderson, Eric.
    - "Swift Lathers and the Mears Newz" (Box 1)
      [58]
  - Bovers, Willian.
    - "'Coughlin Social Justice, and the Youth Movement" (Box 1)
      [59]
  - Dammerman, Marilyn.
    - "The Petty Fuehrer: Anti-Semitism and the Bid for Power" (Box 1)
      [60]
  - Davidson, Peter.
    - "Journalism and Business: The Rise of the Grand Rapids Press" (Box 1)
      [61]
  - Deisch, Phillip.
    - "Newspapers and Labor: Bias in Detroit papers of 'The Battle of the Overpass" (Box 1)
      [62]
- Student Papers, Winter 1973 (cont.)
  - Fisher, Steve.
    - "Hearst, Labor and the Newspapers" (Box 1)
      [63]
  - Gordon, Meryl.
    - "A Study of the 'Women's Stories' in the Detroit Free Press and the Evening News: August 23-December 23, 1873" (Box 1)
      [64]
  - Heuer, Bob.
    - "Interpretive Journalism and the Detroit Riots" (1967) (Box 1)
      [65]
  - Hunt, V. L.
    - "A Comparison of Women's Coverage from 1900 to in the Detroit Evening News" (Box 1)
      [66]
  - Koch, Carol R.
    - "Women's Suffrage in Ann Arbor Newspapers" (Box 1)
      [67]
  - Lenhoff, Alan.
    - "The Detroit News and Early Commercial Radio: Innovation and Exploitation" (Box 1)
      [68]
  - MacNaughton, W. J.
    - "The General Motors Strike of 1945" (Box 1)
      [69]
  - Pontius, Miller.
    - "Three Weeks in Detroit: A Study of the Detroit Press" (Box 1)
      [70]
  - Rives, Lawrence.
    - "Concerning the Early Growth and Development of the Radio in the United States and the Reaction of the Press to It" (Box 1)
      [71]
- Student Papers, Fall 1973
  - Allen, Claudia.
    - "Broadcast License Battles in Clare, Michigan" (Box 1)
      [72]
  - Dreeben, Linda.
    - "Woman Suffrage and the Press" (Box 1)
      [73]
- Student Papers, Winter 1974
  - Adams, Steve.
    - "A Comparative Analysis of the 1907 and 1934 World Series as Covered by The Detroit Free Press and Detroit News" (Box 1)
      [74]
  - Blaess, Thea.
    - "The Pioneer Press, A Northern Example" (Box 1)
      [75]
  - Bonnewell, Dave.
    - "Celebrating Ann's Birthday" (Box 1)
      [76]
  - Chown, Jeffrey.
    - "Auburn Bank Closing" (Box 1)
      [77]
  - DeGroat, Kevin.
    - "The Civil Rights News, The War Against American Fascism" (Box 1)
      [78]
  - Hewens, Bonnie.
    - "Economics of the Huron Daily Tribune" (Box 1)
      [79]
    - "A History of a Small Community Newspaper: The Huron Daily Tribune" (Box 1)
      [80]
  - Howell, Steven.
    - " The Detroit Evening News and The Detroit Free Press: Editorial Viewpoint on the Spanish-American Conflict" (Box 1)
      [81]
  - Irrer, Kathy.
    - " The Michigan Daily: A Chronicle of Student Militarism" (Box 1)
      [82]
  - Jakcsy, John.
    - "Economics of Urban and Rural Michigan Newspapers" (Box 1)
      [83]
  - Johnson, Wayne.
    - "The Thought of Murder" (Box 1)
      (temperance)
      [84]
  - Lamiman, Kevin.
    - "The Lapeer County Press" (Box 1)
      [85]
  - Levick, Diane.
    - "Paul Bunyon: The Media's Subtle Persuasion" (Box 1)
      [86]
  - Lunk, Susan.
    - "The Signal of Liberty as an Organ of Persuasion" (Box 1)
      [87]
  - McGinn, Bob.
    - "Crime Reporting in Detroit: 1880, 1910, 1940" (Box 1)
      [88]
  - Mervak, Gary.
    - "Joint Printing and Michigan Community Papers" (Box 1)
      [89]
  - Simpson, David.
    - "The Three Daily Newspapers of Adrian, Michigan" (Box 1)
      [90]
  - Tamm, Paul.
    - "The Silencing of Fr. Coughlin and Social Justice" (Box 1)
      [91]
  - Vaughn, Laura.
    - "Newspaper Circulation in Michigan Cities, 1974" (Box 1)
      [92]
  - Weed, Mary.
    - "Murrow's Defense of Milo Radulovich in Michigan Papers" (Box 1)
      [93]
  - Willman, Mary.
    - "Examination of Selected Letters from The George Booth Papers" (Box 1)
      [94]
- Student Papers, Fall 1974
  - Hoeltzel,Gerald.
    - "Editorial Independence and the Cook Brothers of The Hastings Banner" (Box 1)
      [95]
- Student Papers, Winter 1975
  - Blackburn, Doug.
    - "Joe Louis. A Comparison Between Four Newspapers and How They Viewed the Rise of the Second Black Heavyweight Champion of the World: The Chicago Defender, The Detroit News, The Detroit Free Press, The Pittsburgh Courier" (Box 2)
      [96]
  - Dudek, Lawrence.
    - " The Fifth Estate and the Counter-Culture" (Box 2)
      [97]
  - Duenas, Anthony R.
    - " Nosotros, Newspaper for Detroit's Latinos 1972-1973" (Box 2)
      [98]
  - Faye, David.
    - "Father Coughlin: His Break with the New Deal" (Box 2)
      [99]
  - Halvaks, Robert.
    - "WPAG and Its Program Mix" (Box 2)
      (Ann Arbor radio station)
      [100]
  - Latka,Linda.
    - "George Corselius and Ann Arbor's First Newspaper" (Box 2)
      [101]
  - Mintz, Cathy.
    - "Detroit Newspapers and the Great Depression" (Box 2)
      [102]
  - Plagefts, James J.
    - "Floyd Miller and the Daily Tribune" [of Royal Oak]. (Box 2)
      [103]
  - Tiberio, Suanne.
    - "Detroit Newspapers and the Election of 1896" (Box 2)
      [104]
  - Wallgreen, Anita.
    - "The Grand Rapids Press Newsboys at the Turn of the Twentieth Century" (Box 2)
      [105]
- Student Papers, Winter 1976
  - Austin, Andrew D.
    - "Eighty-six Years of The Michigan Daily: Have Students Really Changed" (Box 2)
      [106]
  - Boyle, Karen Jo.
    - "The Crockett Crisis Comes to Milford: A Study of Pink Journalism" (Box 2)
      [107]
  - Burke, Sara Larson.
    - " Die Washtenaw Post" (Box 2)
      [108]
  - Huttunen, Laurie J.
    - "Admission of Women to the University of Michigan; A Look at the Press Reaction" (Box 2)
      [109]
  - Korinda, Diane.
    - "Ann Arbor's Frontier Press" (Box 2)
      [110]
  - Lash, Mike.
    - " The Livingston County Press-- its Format and Centennial Coverage in 1876and its Bicentennial Coverage in 1976" (Box 2)
      [111]
  - Long, William F.
    - "The Campus Broadcasting Network, University of Michigan" (Box 2)
      [112]
  - McGuigan, Dave.
    - "Adrian Newspapers at the Turn of the Century" (Box 2)
      [113]
  - Moses, Joan.
    - "Father Coughlin and the Money-Changers -- as told by Four Detroit Newspapers" (Box 2)
      [114]
  - Schulte, Dan.
    - "Father Charles Edward Coughlin -- Mass Media Master" (Box 2)
      [115]
  - Sparks, Lori.
    - "Genesis of Journalism in Niles" (Box 2)
      [116]
  - Theisen, Rick.
    - "The Black Press: A Look at the Black Newspaper The Plaindealer" (Box 2)
      [117]
  - Valant, Michael A.
    - "Dearborn Media: Yesterday and Today" (Box 2)
      [118]
- Student Papers, miscellaneous 1976
  - Born, Corinne.
    - "Continuing Themes in 'the Michigan Union"' (Box 2)
      [119]
  - Hartshorn, Fred.
    - "The Press and Railroad Development in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan Prior to 1890" (Box 2)
      [120]
- Student Papers undated
  - Cameron, Tom.
    - "Henry Ford's effect on the Dearborn Newspapers, 1913-1918" (Box 2)
      [121]
  - Carroll, Blair
    - Untitled (Box 2)
      [122]
  - Damiani, Daniel.
    - " The Signal of Liberty: the Voice of the Anti-Slavery Movement in Michigan from 1841 to 1848" (Box 2)
      [123]
  - Foulkes, Robert.
    - "A View of the Mears Newz from the people who read it" (Box 2)
      [124]
  - Huizenga, Judy.
    - Untitled. (Box 2)
      [125]
  - Mangold, Margaret.
    - "An Analysis of the Michigan Daily as a Reflection of Student Development, 1890-1975" (Box 2)
      [126]
  - Meyerand, Mike.
    - "Theodore Foster-The Man and His Paper" (Box 2)
      [127]
  - Morrison, John.
    - "The Press and a Bridge" (Box 2)
      [128]
  - Parks, Paul.
    - "1831 to 1976: One hundred and forty-five Years of Newspaper Evolution" (Box 2)
      [129]
  - Randolph, Charlie.
    - "The Coverage of University of Michigan Football by Ann Arbor Newspapers from 1890 to the Present" (Box 2)
      [130]
  - Szfranski, Roger A.
    - "The Development of Industry in Detroit with Relationship to the Development of News Reporting" (Box 2)
      [131]
  - Ungar, Bobby.
    - "An Ann Arbor Newspaper Publisher, 1882-1904" (Box 2)
      [132]
  - Waldron, Frances.
    - "The Compromise of 1850 as Reported in Ann Arbor" (Box 2)
      [133]
  - Zaborski, David M.
    - "The Early Evolution of The Battle Creek Enquirer and News" (Box 2)
      [134]
- Student Papers, Fall 1974
  - DeVelbiss, Randy.
    - "The Experience of Being An Editor in a Growing Community" (Box 2)
      [135]
  - Friedler, Eric.
    - "Sports: Is It More Than a Game?" (Box 2)
      [136]
  - Hoeltzel, Gerald.
    - "Editorial Independence and the Cook Brothers of The Hastings Banner" (Box 2)
      [137]
  - Jackson, Jay.
    - "Sensationalism: Did the Detroit Times Use It Against Its Competitors?" (Box 2)
      [138]
  - Meier, Jeffrey L.
    - "Swift Lathers and the Mears Newz" (Box 2)
      [139]
- Student Papers, Fall 1975
  - Beckwith, Peter.
    - "Media at the Race Track" (Box 2)
      [140]
  - Benkarski, John.
    - "A Look at the Small Town Newspaper in Michigan: The Adrian Daily Times and Expositor and The Evening Statesman, 1900-1904" (Box 2)
      [141]
  - Desmond, Sandra.
    - "Father Gabriel Richard" (Box 2)
      [142]
  - DeVore, Don.
    - "An Analysis and Comparison of the Hillsdale Gazette and the Hillsdale Whig Standard" (Box 2)
      [143]
  - Galopin, Gary.
    - " The Signal of Liberty: The Analysis of an Abolitionist Newspaper" (Box 2)
      [144]
  - Ingold, Bernard.
    - " The Sault Ste. Marie News, 1887-1900" (Box 2)
      [145]